Hi I'm Kerri from Zebra and Berkley and I'm here to tell you how to use ear tapers.
An ear taper is the tool used when you are stretching your ears when you are going from one gauge to the next gauge up.
If you look at a taper you will see that there is a small size and a larger size.
A small size ideally is the size that you are currently at.
The larger size is the size that you want to be at.
It kind of resembles a funnel in a way and it funnels your ear to the point where you want it to be at.
When you are using a taper you want to clean the area using some kind of disinfectant or antibacterial soap and water and then you are going to want to lubricate the taper pen with A and D ointment or Neosporin or some kind of Vaseline in order to help it run through your ear smoothly.
When pushing the taper pin through you do want to support it with your hands from the back so you are pushing against something and creating a counter pressure.
That way you are not just pushing your ear into the side of your face with a taper pin.
When you line up the piece of jewelry against the larger size of the taper pin, the size of the jewelry that you want to put in, you want to make sure that you line it up exactly lined up correctly with no gaps or spaces in order to get it in smoothly.
If you are doing it on your own I have seen some people wrap a thin piece of tape around it in order to make sure that you don't lose that connection.
I'm Kerri your favorite piercer and I've done over 200,000 piercings.